Finding aid for the Gene Roddenberry Star Trek Television Series Collection PASC.0062
UCLA Library Special Collections
- PRODUCED EPISODES
  - DAGGER OF THE MIND (Prod# 11)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 4/4/66 - 9/28/66. Total Items: 29 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Perlstein, Ed * Wasson, Susanne * Roddenberry, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean * Robertson, Stanley (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials: Production budget report (2), Daily budget reports (6). Total Items: 8 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - DAY OF THE DOVE (Prod# 66)
    - 1) Story Outline by Jerome Bixby, 3/28/68, 37 pgs. (2 copies) 2) Story Outline, 4/15/68, 19 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 5/7/68, 19 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - 1) Teleplay by Jerome Bixby, 8/2/68, 64 pgs. 2) Final draft teleplay, 8/15/68, 62 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/14/68 - 9/16/68. Total Items: 16 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (6), Photographic Effects (3), Daily Production Reports (6), Call Sheets (6). Total Items: 24 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Reports (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (14), Estimated Finish Cost (18). Total Items: 57 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - THE DEADLY YEARS (Prod# 40)
    - 1) Story Outline by David P. Harmon, 6/5/67, 17 pgs. 2) First draft teleplay, 6/19/67, 68 pgs. 3) Second draft teleplay, 7/3/67, 73 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Harmon, David (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (48), DeForest Research (6). Total Items: 54 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Financial Materials: Contract Request Form (1). Total Items: 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 6/8/67 - 7/24/67. Total Items: 30 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Nimoy, Leonard * Robertson, Stanley * Bay, Don R. * Messerschmidt, Jean * Fontana, D.C. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - THE DEVIL IN THE DARK (Prod# 26)
    - 1) Story outline by Gene Coon, 11/29/66, 15 pgs. (2 copies, 1 w/annotations) 2) Story outline, 12/5/66, 17 pgs. 3) Story outline, 12/5/66, 19 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Coon, Gene (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (14), DeForest Research (12). Total Items: 26 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3, 2 copies), Call Sheets (3), Daily Production Reports (3). Total Items: 12 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 11/30/66 - 3/23/67. Total Items: 7 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Robertson, Stanley * Justman, Robert (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Financial Materials: Production budget report (5), Daily Budget Reports (2). Total Items: 7 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - THE DOOMSDAY MACHINE (Prod# 35)
    - 1) Story Outline by Norman Spinrad, 3/6/67, 13 pgs. 2) Revised teleplay, 4/5/67, 65 pgs. 3) Final draft teleplay, 5/8/67, 64 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Spinrad, Norman (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/7/67 - 5/29/67. Total Items: 65 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Coon, Gene * Fontana, D.C. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Financial Materials: Daily Cost Reports (6), Production Budget Reports (2). Total Items: 8 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - ELAAN OF TROYIUS (Prod# 57)
    - 1) Story Outline by John Meredyth Lucas, 3/8/68, 25 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 3/20/68, w/annotations, 34 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 3/22/68, 31 pgs. 4) Teleplay, 4/12/68, 67 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Lucas, John Meredyth (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (13), DeForest Research (7). Total Items: 20 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 2/21/68 - 6/3/68. Total Items: 36 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Robertson, Stanley * Justman, Robert * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (11), Photographic Effects (3), Daily Production Reports (8), Call Sheets (5). Total Items: 30 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (24), Estimated Finished Cost (32). Total Items: 81 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - THE EMPATH (Prod# 63)
    - 1) Story Outline by Joyce Muskat, 4/26/68, 14 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 5/7/68, 17 pgs. 3) Second draft teleplay, 6/24/68, 68 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Muskat, Joyce (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (6). Total Items: 6 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/29/68 - 8/5/68. Total Items: 14 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (3), Photographic Effects (3), Log (1), Daily Production Reports (8), Call Sheets (7). Total items: 25 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (15), Estimated Finish Cost (22). Total Items: 62 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - THE ENEMY WITHIN (Prod# 5)
    - Treatment by Richard Matheson. n.d., 21 pages. (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1) Teleplay by Richard Matheson, 5/31/66, with annotations, 70 pgs. 2) Teleplay, 6/6/66, w/annotations, 70 pgs. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Script by Richard Matheson, 6/6/66, 70 pages, 2 copies, each with different annotations. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Matheson, Richard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Script materials: Revisions, loose pages (85). Comments on story, pages 1-19, no author (2). DeForest Research (4). Wild Lines/Narration (8). 99 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Production materials: Shooting schedule (11). Projection Room Notes (2). Call Sheets (9). Daily Production Reports (7). Cast List (2). Work Orders (2). Credits (3, 4 copies), Revised Credits (3, 4 copies). Total Items: 57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Desilu Productions, NBC, 4/8/66-8/30/66. 47 items. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Theiss, Bill * Black, John D.F. * Nimoy, Leonard * Madden, Edward * Rode, Don (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Financial materials: Production Budget Reports (9), Photo Effects (1). Total Items: 10 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - THE ENTERPRISE INCIDENT (Prod# 59)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (2), Revisions, loose pages (2). Total Items: 4 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/29/68 - 7/22/68. Total Items: 31 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Messerschmidt, Jean * Robertson, Stanley (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - 1) First draft story outline by D.C. Fontana, 3/29/68, 16 pgs. 2) Revised story outline, 4/19/68, w/annotations, 11 pgs. 3) Revised story outline, 4/22/68, 14 pgs. 4) Final draft teleplay, 6/13/68, 34 pgs. (Incomplete) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Production Materials: Daily Production Reports (6), Shooting Schedule (8), Photographic Effects (3), Credits Breakdown (4), Call Sheets (6). Total Items: 27 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (20), Estimated Finish Cost (28). Total Items: 73 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - ERRAND OF MERCY (Prod# 27)
    - Script materials: DeForest Research (6). Total Items: 6 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Production Materials: Call Sheets (1), Cast List (3), Shooting schedule (2). Total Items: 6 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 1/11/67. Total items: 1 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Reports (4). Total Items: 4 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - FOR THE WORLD IS HOLLOW AND I HAVE TOUCHED THE SKY (Prod# 65)
    - 1) Story Outline by Rik Vollaerts, 5/4/68, 16 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 5/21/68, 15 pgs. (2 copies) 3) Second draft teleplay, 6/17/68, 70 pgs. 4) Second polish teleplay, 7/31/68, 70 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Vollaerts, Rik (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (6). Total Items: 6 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 5/23/68 - 8/19/68. Total Items: 3 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (5), Photographic Effects (4), Daily Production Reports (8), Call Sheets (7). Total Items: 27 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (15), Estimated Finish Cost (20). Total Items: 60 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - FRIDAY'S CHILD (Prod# 32)
    - 1) Story Outline by D.C. Fontana, 1/11/67, 17 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Production Materials: Photographic effects (2). Total Items: 2 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 1/17/67 - 5/22/67. Total Items: 27 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Roddenberry, Gene * Fontana, D.C. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Reports (9). Total Items: 9 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - THE GALILEO SEVEN (Prod# 14)
    - 1) First draft teleplay by Oliver Crawford, 4/25/66, w/annotations, 58 pgs 2) Teleplay by Oliver Crawford, 5/23/66, 67 pgs 3) Teleplay by Shimon Wincelberg and Oliver Crawford (Staff Rewrite), 9/1/66, w/annotations, 59 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Crawford, Oliver (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Story Outline by Oliver Crawford, 4/1/66, 16 pgs, Revisions, loose pages (48), Comments on story pages (1), DeForest Research (4), Comments on staff rewrite (2). Total Items: 55 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Production materials: Credits (3, 3 copies), Shooting schedule (10), Cast list (2), Call sheets (7), Daily production reports (7). Total Items: 35 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 4/4/66 - 9/27/66. Total Items: 46 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Perlstein, Ed * Robertson, Stanley * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Kubichan, Jon * Jefferies, Matt (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Photocopies of sketches of the Galileo Seven shuttle (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials: Production budget report (4), photo effects (1), Daily budget reports (5). Total Items: 10 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - THE GAMESTERS OF TRISKELION (Prod# 46)
    - 1) Story Outline by Margaret Armen, 4/10/67, 21 pgs. 2) Revised story outline, 5/5/67, 9 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 5/8/67, 13 pgs. 4) Revised Story Outline, 5/12/67, 8 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Armen, Margaret (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 1) Teleplay by Margaret Armen, 6/20/67, 73 pgs. 2) Revised Second draft Teleplay, 7/28/67, w/annotations, 78 pgs. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/13/67 - 10/31/67, De Forest Reserch (3). Total Items: 67 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - I, MUDD (Prod# 41)
    - 1) Story Outline by Stephen Kandel, 4/20/67, 6 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 3/23/67, 9 pgs. 3) Teleplay, 5/23/67, 68 pgs. 4) Teleplay, 6/25/67, 68 pgs. 5) Revised final draft teleplay, 8/4/67, 70 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Kandel, Stephen (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (44), DeForest Research (4). Total Items: 48 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/27/67 - 7/26/67. Total Items: 76 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Fontana, D.C. * Coon, Gene * Bay, Don R. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - THE IMMUNITY SYNDROME (Prod# 48)
    - 1) Story Outline by Robert Sabaroff, 8/7/67, 14 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 8/14/67, 13 pgs. 3) First Draft Teleplay, 9/8/67, 62 pgs. 4) Second draft teleplay, 8/9/67, 62 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sabaroff, Robert (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (9). Total items: 9 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, Paramount Television, 8/9/67 - 1/24/68. Total Items: 11 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Fontana, D.C. * Lavery, Emmet (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Financial Materials: Daily Cost Status Reports (3). Total Items: 3 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - IS THERE IN TRUTH NO BEAUTY (Prod# 62)
    - 1) Story Outline by Jean Lisette Aroeste, 5/24/68, 16 pgs. 2) FIrst draft teleplay, 6/18/68, 63 pgs. 3) Revised final draft teleplay, 6/26/68, w/annotations, 65 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Aroeste, Jean Lisette (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 5/9/68 - 8/19/68. Total Items: 10 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Dewey, Ray * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (5), Photographic Effects (2), Call Sheets (7), Daily Production Reports (7). Total Items: 24 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (18), Estimated Finish Cost (25). Total Items: 68 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - JOURNEY TO BABEL (Prod# 44)
    - 1) Story Outline by D.C. Fontana, 6/23/67, 15 pgs. (2 copies) 2) First draft teleplay, 8/8/67, 70 pgs. 3) 2nd Revised draft teleplay, 9/19/67, 64 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (3). Total Items: 3 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 7/5/67 - 9/22/67. Total Items: 22 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Robertson, Stanley * Justman, Robert (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - LET THAT BE YOUR LAST BATTLEFIELD (Prod# 70)
    - 1) Story Outline by Lee Cronin, 3/11/68, 13 pgs. 2) Story Outline by Lee Cronin, 3/22/68, 15 pgs. 3) Teleplay by Oliver Crawford, 9/2/68, 62 pgs. 4) Revised teleplay by Oliver Crawford, 9/23/68, 66 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Cronin, Lee (pseudonym for Gene Coon) * Crawford, Oliver * Trivers, Barry (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - 1) Story Outline by Barry Trivers, 8/8/66, 6 pgs. (2 copies) 2) Story Outline by Barry Trivers, 8/22/66, 5 pgs. (2 copies) 3) 1st draft teleplay by Barry Trivers, 9/28/66, 67 pgs. (2 copies, 1 incomplete) (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (5), Comments on Story Outline (1, 2 copies), Comments on 1st draft by D.C. Fontana (5), Staff Comments on 1st draft (5, 2 copies). Total Items: 22 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 8/15/66 - 10/14/68. Total Items: 21 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Carabatsos, Steven * Coon, Gene * Robertson, Stanley (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Production Materials: Daily Production Report (7), Call Sheets (6), Credits Breakdown (4). Total items: 17 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (10), Estimated Finish Cost (13). Total Items: 48 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - THE LIGHTS OF ZETAR (Prod# 73)
    - 1) Story Outline by Shari Lewis and Jeremy Tarcher, 8/22/68, w/annotations, 18 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 9/6/68, 22 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 9/12/68, 16 pgs. 4) Teleplay, 10/8/68, 71 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Lewis, Shari * Tarcher, Jeremy (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (14). Total Items: 14 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 9/17/68 - 11/11/68. Total Items: 7 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bays, Donald W. * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Production Materials: Notes on Final Cut (1), Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (7), Photographic Effects (4), Daily Production Report (7), Call Sheets (6). Total Items: 28 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (8), Estimated Finished Cost (10). Total Items: 43 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - THE MAN TRAP (Prod# 6)
    - Script by George Clayton Johnson. First draft 6/13/66, with annotations, 67 pages. (Alternate title: DAMSEL WITH A DULCIMER) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Johnson, George Clayton (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Script materials: Revisions, loose pages (23), (39). Comments on story (Chicago Two) page 4-16 (1). DeForest Research (1). Wild Lines/Voice Over (14). Scene Breakdown (5). 83 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Production materials: Editing notes - Narration (7, 2 copies), Dubbing and Scoring Schedule (2), Shooting Schedule (10), Cast list (2), Call sheets (7), Daily Production Reports (8), Credits B. (9), Days-Out-Of-Days (1), Work Orders (3). 48 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 4/8-11/3/66. 48 items. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Rode, Don (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Financial materials: Production Budget/Cost Reports. 10 items. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - THE MARK OF GIDEON (Prod# 72)
    - 1) Treatment by George S. Slavin and Stanley Adams, 6/27/68, 16 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 7/12/68, 17 pgs. (2 copies) 3) Final draft teleplay, 8/28/68, 67 pgs. 4) Revised final draft, 9/25/68, 64 pgs. 5) Final final draft teleplay, 10/11/68, 66 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Slavin, George S. * Adams, Stanley (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Paramount Television, 7/31/68 - 12/16/68. Total Items: 5 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Milkis, Ed * Robertson, Stanley (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Call Sheets (6), Daily Production Reports (7), Notes on Final Cut (1). Total Items: 17 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (8), Estimated Finish Cost (11). Total Items: 44 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - THE MENAGERIE (& MATERIALS FROM "THE CAGE") (Prod# 16)
    - The Cage:1) First draft story outline by Gene Roddenberry, 6/29/64, 26 pgs., 2 copies. 2) Final draft outline, 7/8/64, w/annotations, 21 pgs. 3) Final draft outline, 7/8/64, 11 pgs. (2 copies, 1 w/annotations) 4) Final draft outline, 7/22/64, 11 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1) Rough Draft Outline ("The Cage"), 6/25/64, 14 pgs. 2) Teleplay ("The Cage") by Gene Roddenberry, 8/31/64, 74 pgs. (2 copies) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1) Revised teleplay ("The Cage") by Gene Roddenberry, 10/6/64, w/annotations, 65 pgs. 2) Revised teleplay ("The Menagerie") by Gene Roddenberry, 11/20/64, 73 pgs. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Script materials: Revisions, loose pages of "The Menagerie", Pilot and Episode (158). Total Items: 158 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Script Materials from The Cage & The Menagerie: 1) DeForest Research (8), 2) Narration (1), 3) Dialogue for Trailer (1), 4) Notes on Pilot (1), 5) Comments on "The Cage" (5). Total Items: 16 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Production Materials from The Cage & The Menagerie: Comments on Pilot (23), Dept. and Crew comments (15), Post Production script pages (1), Editing Notes (6), Special Effects List (6), Special effects List (45). Total Items: 96 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Production Materials from The Cage & The Menagerie: Cast Breakdown (1), Cast Lists (232), Call Sheets (26), Daily Production Reports (24), Shooting Schedules (43), Shooting Continuity (4), Special Effects Breakdown (6). Total Items: 130. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Production Materials from The Cage & The Menagerie: Production Schedule (2), Work Order (1), Credits Part I (3, 2 copies), Credits Part II (3, 2 copies), Titles (2). Total Items: 17 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, Howard A. Anderson Co., 7/9/64 - 11/25/66. Total Items: 103. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Bay, Don R. * Chapnick, Morris * Haskin, Byron * Solow, Herb * Smith, Edward G. * Heath, Bill * Perlstein, Ed * Anderson, Darrell A. * Rudin, Mickey * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean * Stahnke, Shirley (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 1) Dictated Rough draft teleplay by Gene Roddenberry, 8/6/64, w/annotations, 93 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages from "The Cage" (16). Total Items: 16 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Financial materials from The Menagerie & The Cage: Effects Budget (4), Overage Rpts (2), Prod. Budget Rpts (14), Daily Budget Rpt (1), MGM Invoices (3),, Cast Costs (3), Cast Breakdown (1), Extra detail (2). Total Items: 30 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - METAMORPHOSIS (Prod# 31)
    - 1) Story Outline by Gene Coon, 4/7/67, 14 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Coon, Gene (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (13), DeForest Research (8). Total Items: 21 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Fontana, D.C. * Hellstrom, Robert * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Reports (10). Total Items: 10 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - MIRI (Prod# 12)
    - 1) Teleplay by Adrian Spies, 8/10/66, w/annotations, 68 pgs., 2 copies. 2) Teleplay, n.d. (Unannotated draft before 8/10/66), 67 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Spies, Adrian (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1) Revised final draft teleplay by Adrian Spies, 8/18/66, w/annotations, 72 pgs. 2) Story Outline, n.d., 16 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 5/16/66, 15 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 4/11/66, w/annotations, 13 pgs. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Script materials: Revisions, loose pages (87), Comments for rewrite (18), Work Orders (2), Staff comments (7), DeForest Research (4). Total Items: 118 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Production materials: Credits (3, 4 copies), Shooting schedule (9), Cast List (2), Call Sheets (7), Daily Production reports (7). Total Items: 37 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/7/66 - 10/28/66. Total Items: 45 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Jefferies, Matt * Robertson, Stanley * Kubichan, Jon * Black, John D.F. (Box 8, Folder 3)